Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
各位英语学习者，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today we are going back in time again and this time we're going to be in the 1960s.
今天我们要再次穿越时空，这次我们要回到20世纪60年代。
That's right.
没错。
We're going to learn some phrases and some slang that were really popular back in 1964.
我们要学习一些在1964年非常流行的短语和俚语。
Exactly.
正是。
And most of these phrases and words we still use today.
而且这些短语和词汇大部分我们今天还在用。
So it's very interesting and very good to know.
所以这很有趣，也很值得了解。
That's right.
没错。
I'm looking forward to this trip back in time.
我很期待这次时光之旅。
So why don't we get started with the dialogue.
那我们开始对话吧。
Hey man, I really like your pad.
嘿，老兄，我真的很喜欢你的公寓。
Those lava lamps are far out.
那些熔岩灯太酷了。
Thanks for letting me crash here tonight.
谢谢你今晚让我借宿。
It's no problem, brother.
没问题，兄弟。
I wanted a pad where people could come, listen to music and just hang loose.
我想要一个地方，人们可以来听音乐，放松自在。
You dig what I'm saying?
你明白我的意思吗？
I dig it, man.
我明白，老兄。
We should throw a bash here and make it a really happening scene.
我们应该在这儿办个派对，让它成为一个热闹的场面。
Yeah, man.
是啊，老兄。
That would be groovy.
那会很棒的。
Hey, I got to split for a while.
嘿，我得离开一会儿。
Are you okay here by yourself?
你一个人在这儿没问题吧？
Don't worry about me, brother.
别担心我，兄弟。
You go take care of your business.
你去忙你的事吧。
All right.
好的。
Peace out.
再见。
All right.
好的。
So great dialogue.
很棒的对话。
Very popular in the 60s.
在60年代非常流行。
The music, the mood and the words, right?
音乐、氛围和用词，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So why don't we get down to business and look at the vocabulary that we saw in this dialogue
那我们不如进入正题，看看对话中出现的词汇。
in Language Takeaway.
在“语言要点”部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Well, the dialogue opened and we heard this guy say, hey man, I really like your pad.
对话一开始，我们听到这个人说：“嘿，老兄，我真的很喜欢你的公寓。”
I really like your pad.
我真的很喜欢你的公寓。
Pad.
公寓。
Okay.
好的。
So pad, a very informal way of saying your apartment, your apartment, right?
所以“pad”是一种非常非正式的说法，指你的公寓，对吧？
And now you can still use it today.
而且现在你仍然可以用它。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
We often hear the expression bachelor pad.
我们经常听到“bachelor pad”这个说法。
Okay.
好的。
A bachelor pad.
单身公寓。
So that's an apartment where a single man lives.
那是指单身男人住的公寓。
Okay.
好的。
So a bachelor pad.
所以是单身公寓。
Usually it's very nicely decorated and really a nice apartment, right?
通常装修得很好，是个很不错的公寓，对吧？
Or maybe it has empty pizza boxes all over the floor, Marco.
或者可能地板上到处都是空披萨盒，Marco。
Also a bachelor pad.
那也是单身公寓。
But so that's what pad means, an apartment.
但这就是“pad”的意思，公寓。
Yeah.
是的。
They were talking about the apartment and he said the lava lamps are far out.
他们在谈论公寓，他说熔岩灯太酷了。
Far out.
太酷了。
Okay.
好的。
It's far out.
太酷了。
So that's really cool or amazing.
那意思是真的很酷或很棒。
Right.
对。
And now lava lamps, those are those strange cone looking lamps, right?
现在熔岩灯，就是那些奇怪的锥形灯，对吧？
Kind of a light with like some liquid moving inside.
一种里面有液体流动的灯。
Moving inside.
里面流动。
Very popular in the 60s.
在60年代非常流行。
Yeah.
是的。
We'll post some pictures of that.
我们会贴一些图片。
Yeah.
是的。
And the lamps are far out.
这些灯太酷了。
So now you can use that with other things, right?
所以你现在可以用它来形容其他东西，对吧？
Like you are really far out.
比如你真的很酷。
Yeah.
是的。
Or this music is really far out.
或者这音乐真的很酷。
Okay.
好的。
It kind of gives you the feeling like it's sort of spacey.
它给人一种有点迷幻的感觉。
Yeah.
是的。
All right.
好的。
So the pad is really far out.
所以这个公寓真的很酷。
The lava lamps are great.
熔岩灯很棒。
And he was saying, thanks for letting me crash here tonight.
他说：“谢谢你今晚让我借宿。”
To crash.
借宿。
So to crash at someone's place.
所以是在某人家里借宿。
Right.
对。
So we're not talking about like a car crash here.
我们这里说的不是车祸。
No, no, no.
不，不，不。
But so when you crash somewhere, what do you do?
但当你“crash”在某个地方时，你做什么？
Well, you are staying there.
嗯，你待在那里。
Then you're going to stay there.
你会待在那里。
So you're going to...
所以你会……
As a guest.
作为客人。
Yeah.
是的。
So like sleep, right?
就像睡觉，对吧？
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
Yep.
是的。
So if for example, you're going to New York and you're going to visit a friend, you might
所以比如，你要去纽约拜访朋友，你可能会在朋友家借宿。
crash at your friend's house.
在朋友家借宿。
That's right.
没错。
So interesting word.
很有趣的词。
And it is quite commonly used now.
而且现在也很常用。
So why don't we hear some examples of how we can use it?
那我们听一些例子，看看怎么用。
Example one.
例子一。
Hey man, can I crash at your place tonight?
嘿，老兄，我今晚能在你家借宿吗？
Example two.
例子二。
I lost my key.
我丢了钥匙。
So I'm crashing at my girlfriend's house.
所以我在女朋友家借宿。
Example three.
例子三。
No you've been sleeping on my couch for a month.
不，你已经在我沙发上睡了一个月了。
You're not going to crash here tonight.
你今晚不能在这儿借宿。
All right.
好的。
Perfect.
完美。
So to crash, right?
所以“to crash”，对吧？
It's still commonly used today.
现在仍然常用。
Yeah.
是的。
Now for the fourth word, groovy.
现在第四个词，“groovy”。
Groovy.
很棒。
That would be groovy.
那会很棒。
So again, this means like great or cool or really nice.
同样，这意思是很好、很酷或很不错。
Yeah.
是的。
This is, I think this is one of the main words of the 1960s.
我觉得这是20世纪60年代的主要词汇之一。
Everything was groovy.
一切都很棒。
Yes, I agree.
是的，我同意。
So it kind of gives you the sense that it's sort of really cool, but in a relaxed way.
它给人一种很酷但很放松的感觉。
Yeah, it's groovy.
是的，很棒。
This music is really groovy.
这音乐真的很棒。
That's right.
没错。
And finally, his friend, he said, hey, I got to split for a while.
最后，他的朋友说：“嘿，我得离开一会儿。”
To split.
离开。
Okay.
好的。
So if I say I have to split.
所以如果我说“I have to split”。
You have to leave.
你得走了。
I have to leave.
我得走了。
Yeah.
是的。
Very colloquial.
很口语化。
And it means I have to leave for a little bit.
意思是我得离开一会儿。
Yeah.
是的。
Split for a while.
离开一会儿。
That's right.
没错。
We've heard this one before.
我们以前听过这个。
So why don't we hear some examples to help you understand how it's used.
那我们听一些例子，帮助你理解怎么用。
Example one.
例子一。
Hurry up.
快点。
We've got to split before the police get here.
我们得在警察来之前离开。
Example two.
例子二。
This party is boring.
这个派对很无聊。
Let's split.
我们走吧。
Example three.
例子三。
I have to wake up early tomorrow, so we're going to split.
我明天要早起，所以我们得走了。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
So split.
所以“split”。
Now also, I think you can use it for relationships, right?
另外，我觉得你也可以用在关系上，对吧？
Me and him, me and her split up.
我和他，我和她分手了。
That's right.
没错。
So you ended your relationship.
所以你们结束了关系。
Yeah.
是的。
Split.
分手。
Okay.
好的。
So we saw five really common phrases from the 1960s.
所以我们看到了五个60年代非常常见的短语。
Let's listen to the dialogue again a little bit slower, and then we'll come back and look
让我们再听一遍对话，慢一点，然后回来看看60年代的一些短语。
at some phrases from the 60s.
60年代的短语。
Hey man, I really like your pad.
嘿，老兄，我真的很喜欢你的公寓。
Those lava lamps are far out.
那些熔岩灯太酷了。
Thanks for letting me crash here tonight.
谢谢你今晚让我借宿。
It's no problem, brother.
没问题，兄弟。
I wanted a pad where people could come, listen to music, and just hang loose.
我想要一个地方，人们可以来听音乐，放松自在。
You dig what I'm saying?
你明白我的意思吗？
I dig it, man.
我明白，老兄。
We could throw a bash here and make it a really happening scene.
我们可以在这儿办个派对，让它成为一个热闹的场面。
Yeah, man.
是啊，老兄。
That would be groovy.
那会很棒的。
Hey, I got to split for a while.
嘿，我得离开一会儿。
Are you okay here by yourself?
你一个人在这儿没问题吧？
Don't worry about me, brother.
别担心我，兄弟。
You go take care of your business.
你去忙你的事吧。
All right.
好的。
Peace out.
再见。
All right.
好的。
Well, I want to get started at looking at these 1960s slang phrases.
我想开始看看这些60年代的俚语短语。
So let's go now with putting it together.
那我们现在进入“整合”部分。
Putting it together.
整合。
All right.
好的。
I'm putting it together today.
今天我来整合。
Let's start with the first part.
我们从第一部分开始。
He talked about, you dig what I'm saying?
他谈到：“你明白我的意思吗？”
I dig it, man.
“我明白，老兄。”
You dig what I'm saying?
你明白我的意思吗？
To dig it.
明白。
All right.
好的。
So we know the verb dig, which means to make a hole, right?
我们知道动词“dig”意思是挖洞，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
But now he's talking about understand.
但现在他是在说理解。
Yeah.
是的。
Basically, you dig what I'm saying.
基本上，“你明白我的意思吗？”
Do you understand what I'm saying?
你理解我在说什么吗？
And when he says, I dig it, he says, I understand.
当他说“我明白”时，他说我理解。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
And there's also another meaning to this, right?
而且这个词还有另一个意思，对吧？
Apart from understand.
除了理解之外。
Yeah.
是的。
It can also mean I like it.
它也可以表示我喜欢。
Okay.
好的。
So I really dig this type of music.
所以我真的很喜欢这种音乐。
Or I really dig this restaurant.
或者我真的很喜欢这家餐厅。
Okay.
好的。
So it's kind of, I like it.
所以这有点像，我喜欢它。
All right.
好的。
Now moving on, he said we could throw a bash here.
现在继续，他说我们可以在这里办个派对。
All right.
好的。
Throw a bash.
办个派对。
To throw a bash.
So first of all, what is a bash?
那么首先，什么是“bash”？
A bash is a party.
“Bash”就是派对。
A really great party.
一个很棒的派对。
An amazing party.
一个超棒的派对。
Now I want to look at this verb to throw something.
现在我想看看“throw something”这个动词。
So we know that you throw a ball, right?
我们知道你可以扔一个球，对吧？
Right.
对。
But how can you throw a party?
但你怎么能“扔”一个派对呢？
Well, it's basically saying you organize or you host a party.
嗯，基本上就是说你组织或举办一个派对。
Okay.
好的。
And how can you use this phrase?
那你怎么用这个短语呢？
Okay.
好的。
So I can say, last week I threw a birthday party in my house.
所以我可以这样说，上周我在家办了一个生日派对。
Okay.
好的。
Or let's throw a bash to celebrate your engagement.
或者咱们办个派对庆祝你订婚。
Okay.
好的。
Or next week I'm going to throw a dinner party at my house.
或者下周我要在家办个晚宴派对。
Okay.
好的。
So to throw a party.
所以就是“办个派对”。
And it's usually used for parties, right?
而且它通常用于派对，对吧？
Right.
对。
You wouldn't throw a...
你不会说办个……
Throw a meeting.
办个会议。
All right.
好的。
No.
不会。
Okay.
好的。
So now we heard them use the word man a lot, right?
现在我们听到他们经常用“man”这个词，对吧？
Hey man.
嘿，老兄。
Yeah.
是的。
That's right.
没错。
Now this is so common, even in modern English, that I think we need some examples.
这在现代英语中非常常见，我觉得我们需要一些例子。
Example one.
例子一。
Hey man, watch where you're going.
嘿，老兄，看路。
Example two.
例子二。
Yeah, man, that's a great idea.
是啊，老兄，那是个好主意。
Example three.
例子三。
Man, that was awesome.
老兄，那太棒了。
So man is one of those words that you just use at the end of your sentences.
所以“man”是那种你放在句子末尾用的词。
Or the beginning.
或者开头。
Anywhere.
任何地方。
And so you say, hey man, or yeah man.
所以你可以说，嘿，老兄，或者是啊，老兄。
Yeah.
是的。
What about, do you have to be a man to use it?
那是不是必须得是男人才能用这个词？
Or do you have to be talking to a man to use it?
或者你必须跟男人说话才能用？
No, not really.
不，不一定。
Men and women use the word man.
男人和女人都用“man”这个词。
And you can call a girl like, hey man, how are you?
你也可以对一个女孩说，嘿，老兄，你好吗？
Yeah.
是的。
But that sort of means that she's a really, really good friend.
但这意味着她是非常非常好的朋友。
Like the same level of friend as your guy friends.
就像和你男性朋友一样的亲密程度。
Yeah.
是的。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
And now for the last phrase, I'm putting it together.
现在最后一个短语，我把它们整合起来。
He said, you go take care of business.
他说，你去处理你的事。
You take care of business.
你处理你的事。
Okay.
好的。
So I have to take care of business.
所以我得处理我的事。
So we're not really talking about business and work here, are we?
但我们这里不是真的在说生意和工作，对吧？
No, no, no.
不，不，不。
So basically what we're saying is, go handle your affairs.
所以基本上我们说的是，去处理你的事情。
So do the things you have to do.
就是做你必须做的事。
Okay.
好的。
So, or solve your problems.
所以，或者解决你的问题。
So if I say, I have to go to City Hall today and take care of some business.
所以如果我说，我今天得去市政厅处理一些事。
So you're maybe going to do something like...
所以你可能是去做一些像……
Pay my taxes or something like that.
交税之类的事情。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So we heard some great phrases.
所以我们听到了一些很棒的短语。
We saw these words.
我们看到了这些词。
Let's listen to the dialogue for the last time, and then we'll come back and talk about
让我们最后听一遍对话，然后回来聊聊这个伟大的十年。
this great decade.
这个伟大的十年。
Hey man, I really like your pad.
嘿，老兄，我真的很喜欢你的住处。
Those lava lamps are far out.
那些熔岩灯太酷了。
Thanks for letting me crash here tonight.
谢谢你今晚让我借宿。
It's no problem, brother.
没问题，兄弟。
I wanted a pad where people could come, listen to music and just hang loose.
我想要一个地方，人们可以来，听音乐，放松自在。
You dig what I'm saying?
你懂我的意思吗？
I dig it, man.
我懂，老兄。
We should throw a bash here and make it a really happening scene.
我们应该在这儿办个派对，让它成为一个热闹的场面。
Yeah, man, that would be groovy.
是啊，老兄，那会很棒的。
Hey, I got to split for a while.
嘿，我得先走一会儿。
Are you okay here by yourself?
你一个人在这儿行吗？
Don't worry about me, brother.
别担心我，兄弟。
You go take care of your business.
你去处理你的事吧。
All right.
好的。
Peace out.
再见。
All right.
好的。
So 1960s, very famous among rock music, the peace and conflicts and all this stuff.
所以20世纪60年代，在摇滚乐、和平与冲突等等方面非常出名。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
I guess in English or Anglo pop culture, we look back at this decade very fondly.
我想在英语或盎格鲁流行文化中，我们非常怀念这个十年。
Yeah.
是的。
And also we really related to the hippie movement, right?
而且我们也非常认同嬉皮士运动，对吧？
People with long hair and baggy clothes, living in their cars, going from concert to concert.
留着长发、穿着宽松衣服的人，住在车里，从一个演唱会跑到另一个。
Yeah.
是的。
And I mean, speaking of music, I think if we think 1960s, at least in Anglo world, we
我的意思是，说到音乐，我想如果我们想到20世纪60年代，至少在盎格鲁世界，我们会想到最好的音乐。
think of the best music.
我们会想到最好的音乐。
I think this is the golden age of music in English speaking countries.
我认为这是英语国家音乐的黄金时代。
Yes, it was a very good era.
是的，那是一个非常棒的时代。
And well, what do you guys think?
那么，你们觉得呢？
Do you think the 60s was the best decade or maybe you are more fond of the 70s, the disco
你们觉得60年代是最好的十年，还是你们更喜欢70年代，迪斯科时代？
era?
迪斯科时代？
Or even the 90s.
或者甚至是90年代。
There's some pretty good music in 1994.
1994年有一些相当不错的音乐。
Exactly.
没错。
So come to our website and let us know what you think.
所以来我们的网站告诉我们你的想法。
And also if you have any questions or comments.
如果你有任何问题或评论。
Marco and I are always around to answer your questions.
Marco和我随时都在回答你们的问题。
So thanks for downloading and until next time.
所以感谢下载，下次见。
Goodbye.
再见。
Bye.